<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="509" CreationDate="2009-04-30T06:49:01.807" Score="13" ViewCount="903" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our nightly full (and periodic differential) backups are becoming quite large, due mostly to the amount of indexes on our tables; roughly half the backup size is comprised of indexes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We're using the &lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt; recovery model for our backups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there any way, through using &lt;code&gt;FileGroups&lt;/code&gt; or some other file-partitioning method, to &lt;strong&gt;exclude&lt;/strong&gt; indexes from the backups?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if this could be extended to full-text catalogs, as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3" LastEditorUserId="919" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T02:11:16.667" LastActivityDate="2009-05-10T15:22:39.707" Title="How to exclude indexes from backups in SQL Server 2008" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;backup&gt;&lt;sql-server-2008&gt;&lt;indexes&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1238" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:04:18.883" Score="18" ViewCount="1951" Body="&lt;p&gt;We've struggled with the RAID controller in our database server, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pc.ibm.com/europe/server/index.html?nl&amp;amp;cc=nl&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lenovo ThinkServer&lt;/a&gt; RD120. It is a rebranded Adaptec that Lenovo / IBM dubs the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/abstracts/tips0054.html#ServeRAID-8k&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ServeRAID 8k&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have patched this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/abstracts/tips0054.html#ServeRAID-8k&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ServeRAID 8k&lt;/a&gt; up to the very latest and greatest:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;RAID bios version&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;RAID backplane bios version&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Windows Server 2008 driver&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This RAID controller has had multiple critical BIOS updates even in the short 4 month time we've owned it, and the &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.software.ibm.com/systems/support/system%5Fx/ibm%5Ffw%5Faacraid%5F5.2.0-15427%5Fanyos%5F32-64.chg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;change history&lt;/a&gt; is just.. well, scary. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We've tried both write-back and write-through strategies on the logical RAID drives. &lt;strong&gt;We still get intermittent I/O errors under heavy disk activity.&lt;/strong&gt; They are not common, but serious when they happen, as they cause SQL Server 2008 I/O timeouts and sometimes failure of SQL connection pools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were at the end of our rope troubleshooting this problem. Short of hardcore stuff like replacing the entire server, or replacing the RAID hardware, we were getting desperate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first got the server, I had a problem where drive bay #6 wasn't recognized. Switching out hard drives to a different brand, strangely, fixed this -- and updating the RAID BIOS (for the first of many times) fixed it permanently, so I was able to use the original &quot;incompatible&quot; drive in bay 6. On a hunch, I began to assume that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822136143&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the Western Digital SATA hard drives&lt;/a&gt; I chose  were somehow incompatible with the ServeRAID 8k controller.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buying 6 new hard drives was one of the cheaper options on the table, so I went for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822145215&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;6 Hitachi (aka IBM, aka Lenovo) hard drives&lt;/a&gt; under the theory that an IBM/Lenovo RAID controller is more likely to work with the drives it's typically sold with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looks like that hunch paid off -- we've been through three of our heaviest load days (mon,tue,wed) without a single I/O error of any kind. Prior to this we regularly had at least one I/O &quot;event&quot; in this time frame. &lt;strong&gt;It sure looks like switching brands of hard drive has fixed our intermittent RAID I/O problems!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I understand that IBM/Lenovo probably tests their RAID controller exclusively with their own brand of hard drives, I'm disturbed that a RAID controller would have such subtle I/O problems with particular brands of hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So my question is, &lt;strong&gt;is this sort of SATA drive incompatibility common with RAID controllers?&lt;/strong&gt; Are there some brands of drives that work better than others, or are &quot;validated&quot; against particular RAID controller? I had sort of assumed that all commodity SATA hard drives were alike and would work reasonably well in any given RAID controller (of sufficient quality).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1" LastActivityDate="2011-03-08T08:18:15.380" Title="Do RAID controllers commonly have SATA drive brand compatibility issues?" Tags="&lt;raid&gt;&lt;ibm&gt;&lt;lenovo&gt;&lt;serveraid8k&gt;" AnswerCount="8" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="104" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:48:06.750" Score="26" ViewCount="692" Body="&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do you keep your servers up to date?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When using a package manager like &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.debian.org/Aptitude&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Aptitude&lt;/a&gt;, do you keep an upgrade / install history, and if so, how do you do it?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When installing or upgrading packages on multiple servers, are there any ways to speed the process up as much as possible?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="22" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:05:02.217" LastActivityDate="2009-06-05T04:01:09.423" Title="Best practices for keeping UNIX packages up to date?" Tags="&lt;unix&gt;&lt;package-management&gt;&lt;server-management&gt;" AnswerCount="11" FavoriteCount="14" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:49:58.027" Score="10" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Regarding your third question: I always run a local repository. Even if it's only for one machine, it saves time in case I need to reinstall (I generally use something like aptitude autoclean), and for two machines, it almost always pays off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the clusters I admin, I don't generally keep explicit logs: I let the package manager do it for me. However, for those machines (as opposed to desktops), I don't use automatic installations, so I do have my notes about what I intended to install to all machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="28" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:49:58.027" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:56:20.070" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't think it's common per se. However, as soon as you start using enterprise storage controllers, whether that be SAN's or standalone RAID controllers, you'll generally want to adhere to their compatibility list rather closely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may be able to save some bucks on the sticker price by buying a cheap range of disks, but that's probably one of the last areas I'd want to save money on - given the importance of data in most scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In other words, explicit incompatibility is very uncommon, but explicit compatibility adherence is recommendable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:56:20.070" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="537" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:06.247" Score="8" ViewCount="2648" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our database currently only has one FileGroup, PRIMARY, which contains roughly 8GB of data (table rows, indexes, full-text catalog).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When is a good time to split this into secondary data files?  What are some criteria that I should be aware of?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3" LastActivityDate="2009-07-08T07:23:49.527" Title="In SQL Server, when should you split your PRIMARY Data FileGroup into secondary data files?" Tags="&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;files&gt;&lt;filegroups&gt;" AnswerCount="3" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="17" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:09.117" Score="12" ViewCount="529" Body="&lt;p&gt;What enterprise virus-scanning systems do you recommend?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T11:51:09.290" Title="What is the best enterprise virus-scanning system?" Tags="&lt;antivirus&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:57:15.653" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;You can have a local repository and configure all servers to point to it for updates. Not only you get speed of local downloads, you also get to control which official updates you want installed on your infrastructure in order to prevent any compatibility issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the Windows side of things, I've used &lt;a href=&quot;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/wsus/default.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Windows Server Update Services&lt;/a&gt; with very satisfying results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="36" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T07:57:15.653" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="38" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:58:11.033" Score="8" ViewCount="1172" Body="&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm chasing a pipe dream here, but I'd really like to find an easy to use backup solution that supports both Windows and OS X, presumably something people never have to think about until the worst happens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="27" LastEditorUserId="919" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T02:10:53.753" LastActivityDate="2010-09-02T19:27:12.807" Title="Best mixed environment (OS X + Windows) backup?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;backup&gt;&lt;macosx&gt;" AnswerCount="9" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="11" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:58:55.523" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The primary reason is performance. When you run out of IOPS capacity on your primary filegroup disk drive, you'll need to expand onto a second filegroup to split IOPS over multiple disks/LUNs depending on storage config.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EDIT:&#xA;Brad Wilson made a good comment regarding SSDs. If you're using a composite SSD/SATA/FC storage system, you may want to have different filegroups on different types of storage. You can then put your extreme IOPS requirement tables onto SSD filegropus, while history/stats tables may be stored on cheap SATA filegroups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="24" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:17:01.860" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:17:01.860" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="12" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="394" CreationDate="2009-04-30T07:59:31.013" Score="1" ViewCount="277" Body="&lt;p&gt;[This was originally posted at stackoverflow.com but might be more suitable here and I'm sure it's a server configuration issue. Apologies if this is considered bad form.]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of our database revision control (and auto-installation) procedures we need to be able run sqlcmd.exe on various .sql files from within an ASP page. The code I'm using to do this is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dim cmd : cmd = &quot;sqlcmd -S &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_SERVER &amp;amp; &quot; -U &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_UID &amp;amp; &quot; -P &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_PWD &amp;amp; &quot; -d &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_NAME &amp;amp; &quot; -i &quot;&quot;&quot; &amp;amp; scriptPath &amp;amp; &quot;&quot;&quot; -b&quot;&#xA;Dim wshShell : Set wshShell = Server.CreateObject(&quot;WScript.Shell&quot;)&#xA;Dim return : return = wshShell.Run(cmd, 0, True)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have the code working fine on two separate development machines. These are both running XP and required no additionally steps to get the code working. Having deployed the code to a Windows 2003 server it's having problems. The problem being that the value for return is always 1. This also happens if I try to get it to run a batch file or anything else I can think of (if I change the value for cmd to an non-existing file it bombs out as I'd expect)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've tried adding I_USR and I_WAM to have execute permissions on both sqlcmd.exe and cmd.exe but it still returns 1. If I open a command prompt at the server and do a &quot;runas /user:servername\i_usr sqlcmd.exe&quot; that works fine but running from the ASP page still doesn't work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, when running the .sql scripts manually everything runs smoothly so there's no problem with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there any security settings on the server that I've forgotten to change within IIS or Windows generally to make it work?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have also tried this on another Server 2003 machine and am getting exactly the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Halp.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastEditorUserId="3038" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-06-17T00:21:54.520" LastActivityDate="2009-06-17T00:21:54.520" Title="Running an .exe from an .asp file using wscipt under Windows Server 2003" Tags="&lt;windows-server-2003&gt;&lt;wscript&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="13" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="7" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:06.207" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;In the past I have used Symantec Corporate Edition quite extensively. Whilst their Norton products have a bad rap (for good reason) for being slow, the corporate version was pretty quick and unobtrusive and had a good managment console. However that was a few years ago so they could have ruined it by now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've recently had to use kaspersky and I don't recommend it from what I saw. It may have been the version I was given but the centralised management features were a bit of a joke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:00:06.207" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="15" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="152" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:58.000" Score="2" ViewCount="437" Body="&lt;p&gt;My System is a Ubuntu 7.10 LTS. I have a (soft) Raid 6 with 5 disks (Samsung 500GB SATA disks), formatted with jsf. Should I upgrade to 8.10 LTS or isn't it worth the hassle? What are the chances that something could happen to the raid configuration? I don't want to be in the position to rebuild the raid from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="44" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T14:38:56.857" Title="(Soft) Raid 6 on Ubuntu 7.10 LTS, should I migrate to 8.10 LTS?" Tags="&lt;linux&gt;&lt;ubuntu&gt;&lt;raid&gt;" AnswerCount="2" />
  <row Id="16" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="22" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:00:58.220" Score="5" ViewCount="486" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a website that a number of customers are using to host their sites.  They each have their own domain name, but are using the same hosted service.  Is it better to have them run off the same IIS website with all the host headers on that site, or should I create a different website &amp;amp; app pool for each domain that point at the same physical directory on the server?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastEditorUserId="38" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-01T04:25:18.430" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T04:25:18.430" Title="Are there any issues with having multiple IIS websites pointing at the same folder?" Tags="&lt;iis&gt;&lt;hosting&gt;&lt;web-hosting&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="17" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="7" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:01:14.240" Score="13" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;We use NOD32. The main reason for choosing it was because it was less of a resource-hog than the others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:01:14.240" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="20" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="16" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:04:56.337" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are no problems with running multiple sites from the same folder, I have done it many times. The advantage you gain by running separate sites in separate app pools is resilience to crashes, if an error is caused in one site, it is less likely to affect the others. It also means that if one site is more popular than the others you can alter the pool settings to make that more efficient when recycling threads if required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:04:56.337" />
  <row Id="21" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="32" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:04:57.850" Score="14" ViewCount="365" Body="&lt;p&gt;What's the top the reason you're unable - or unwilling - to upgrade to the latest available operating system verions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastEditorUserId="2546" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-25T13:47:41.273" LastActivityDate="2009-05-25T21:28:49.117" Title="What prevents you from upgrading to newer operating system versions?" Tags="&lt;upgrade&gt;&lt;operating-system&gt;" AnswerCount="19" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="22" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="16" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:05:22.170" Score="7" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;No reason to use multiple app pools unless you have an explicit reason for separating them. Otherwise it's just waste of memory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There shouldn't be any issues in running multiple websites off the same directory. If at some point a client needs a different version, you can migrate them onto a different dir with a specialized code base / config / etc. If this is a scenario that might occur more often, then you might consider separating them onto different websites up front.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:05:22.170" />
  <row Id="23" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="34" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:06:27.020" Score="11" ViewCount="368" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am looking for open source applications that will allow resizing hard drive partitions. I have used partition magic in the past but am looking for open source free applications that can handle this task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="2" LastEditorUserId="2" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:12:42.043" LastActivityDate="2009-05-02T10:13:12.860" Title="Open source applications for resizing drive partitions" Tags="&lt;partition&gt;&lt;resize&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="4" />
  <row Id="24" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:06:38.500" Score="2" ViewCount="325" Body="&lt;p&gt;Originally my system had two SATA disk drives - I added an extra SATA disk drive to my system and when accessing this disk it sometimes take about 50 times longer to access the drive. (Windows Explorer can take about 2 mins to populate the basic directory and there is nothing special about the directory)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This doesn't happen all the time, but can't identify a pattern at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any ideas what I've done wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Using Windows Vista Home Premium - PC is custom made - this is just on my development PC. What other useful info can I give?)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T21:27:47.513" Title="Why does my disk drive access slow so much after adding a new drive?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;diskdrive&gt;" AnswerCount="2" />
  <row Id="25" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:06:50.497" Score="7" ViewCount="1426" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am looking for a backup solution for this scenario:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 servers (One Linux mail server, 2 Windows Servers)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;~ 10TB of data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 TB of which are in daily use&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a few GB of activity/change per day&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ability to restore data from any point in time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;backing up is performed on a live system (international office)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A MSSQL database needs backing up as well&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no sufficient network connection to back data up off-site&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Uncomplicated access (native file system) to the secured data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the moment the backing up of data is handled by carrying out the delta on portable disks to an off-site location. But the software is not completely reliable (something home cooked).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We pondered whether to purchase a tape library solution from Dell, but are not very convinced that tapes are the way to go for this relatively small amout of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How would you set up this kind of data backup?&#xA;What software would you recommend?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carrying disks with the delta to an off-site server to a mirror server is an option. What kind of hardware would you use?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="49" LastActivityDate="2009-06-04T11:13:24.360" Title="Backup solution for 10TB of data and 3 servers" Tags="&lt;backup&gt;" AnswerCount="3" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="26" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="493" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:01.840" Score="6" ViewCount="243" Body="&lt;p&gt;Does a clean install of PowerShell on its own have enough functionally to Admin a Windows domain environment and/or SQL Servers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If not what are good, free or pay for, third party add-ons?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="52" LastActivityDate="2009-05-18T17:27:16.177" Title="Is Vanilla Powershell Enough of a Language for Windows &amp; DB Server Admins?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;sql-server&gt;&lt;powershell&gt;" AnswerCount="8" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="27" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:27.157" Score="11" ViewCount="474" Body="&lt;p&gt;Which cloud computing provider would you recomend for a windows stack, in terms of cost and reliability?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="7342" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-06-06T08:02:56.047" LastActivityDate="2009-06-06T08:02:56.047" ClosedDate="2009-04-30T18:16:50.657" Title="What is your favorite cloud computing provider?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;hosting&gt;&lt;cloud-computing&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="28" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:30.340" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As far as windows is concerned, before the 1st service pack is almost always buggy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pretty much in that order&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:07:30.340" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="29" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:52.820" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm usually keen to upgrade to the latest versions of an OS, however the most common reasons I have found for people not want to upgrade is either the compatability of old software, or not wanting to learn a new OS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:07:52.820" />
  <row Id="30" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="41" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:07:55.270" Score="35" ViewCount="1605" Body="&lt;p&gt;Users can't get to their e-mail, the CEO can't get to the company's home page, and your pager just went off with a &quot;911&quot; code. What do you do when everything blows up?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastEditorUserId="1" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2010-08-07T05:48:10.303" LastActivityDate="2010-08-07T05:48:10.303" Title="What's your checklist for when everything blows up?" Tags="&lt;checklist&gt;" AnswerCount="21" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="20" />
  <row Id="31" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:08:34.893" Score="5" ViewCount="247" Body="&lt;p&gt;As I see it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Microsoft has always provided backward compatibility for legacy applications;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As far as the end user is concerned, things won't be behaving any different from what they normally expect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="55" LastEditorUserId="1433" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-06T06:03:54.597" LastActivityDate="2009-05-06T06:03:54.597" Title="Why is Virtual PC being bundled with Windows 7 significant?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;virtualization&gt;&lt;compatibility&gt;&lt;legacy&gt;" AnswerCount="9" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="32" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:18.447" Score="26" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The current one just works!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:09:18.447" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="33" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="46" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:20.320" Score="2" ViewCount="244" Body="&lt;p&gt;Can I install Exchange 2007 onto a Windows 2008 single server, which will be the only server in the LAN? I'm guessing this server will also have the AD on it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="58" LastEditorUserId="123" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T06:31:16.667" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T06:31:16.667" Title="It is possible to install Exchange Server on a single W2008 server?" Tags="&lt;windows-server-2008&gt;&lt;exchange-2007&gt;" AnswerCount="3" />
  <row Id="34" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="23" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:31.473" Score="15" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've used &lt;a href=&quot;http://gparted.sourceforge.net/livecd.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;GParted Live CD&lt;/a&gt; in the past with success, it's a linux boot disk designed for partitoning.  I should have mentioned that despite being a linux disk, it works for sorting out windows partitions too.  I split my laptop up to install the windows 7 beta using this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastEditorUserId="38" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-02T10:13:12.860" LastActivityDate="2009-05-02T10:13:12.860" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="35" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="61" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:38.727" Score="4" ViewCount="203" Body="&lt;p&gt;What commercial or open-source tools are available to measure bandwidth utilization on a network? The tools should provide current and historical snapshots.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="61" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:18:34.137" Title="Bandwidth utilization tools?" Tags="&lt;networking&gt;" AnswerCount="1" />
  <row Id="36" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.523" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The hassle of reinstalling all my applications is the #1 reason for me. That and the fact that even after I reinstall, there'll most probably be incompatibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.523" />
  <row Id="37" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="26" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.680" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Powershell doesn't ship with SQL administration tools, although you could continue to use things like osql or isql. I know there are Powershell addins that let you &quot;mount&quot; a SQL server and navigate it like it was a file system (much like the Registry stuff that's built in).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="27" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:09:48.680" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="38" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="10" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:09:55.450" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozy.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mozy&lt;/a&gt; on both OSX (primarly) and Windows for over a year now with few problems, including during testing of recovery. The biggest problem, which I don't think is solved by any backup solution, is the slowing of the computer caused by encoding or determining which files need to be backed up. Also, Mozy is very cheap and they have both enterprise (reasonable pricing) and personal backup solutions (especially cheap) There are other similar services out there now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another service that seems quite similar is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Blackblaze&lt;/a&gt;. Similar pricing and services to that of Mozy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastEditorUserId="25" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-01T18:45:07.273" LastActivityDate="2009-05-01T18:45:07.273" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="39" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:10:01.520" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Upgrading the OS on a server that is hosting lots of websites means many many hours reinstalling the sites on the new server, not to mention the downtime and the ever-present risk of missing some undocumented third-party component or service installed on the old server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same is true on a personal computer (though more of the work goes into reinstalling applications, and reconfiguring the environment).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it ain't broke, don't fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="34" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:10:01.520" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="40" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="83" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:10:19.507" Score="5" ViewCount="357" Body="&lt;p&gt;What is the best backup strategy for saving IIS 6.0 data: web metadata, files, logs etc. for disaster recovery?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="45" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:24:52.310" Title="Best practice for IIS 6.0 (Windows Server 2003) backups?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;windows-server-2003&gt;&lt;iis&gt;&lt;backup&gt;&lt;disaster-recovery&gt;" AnswerCount="2" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="41" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="30" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:10:38.290" Score="33" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The first answer is stay calm! I learned that the hard way that panicking often just makes things worse. Once thats achieved the next thing is to actually ascertain what the problem is. Complaints from users and managers will be coming at you from all angles, telling you what THEY cannot do, but not what the problem is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you know the problem you can start the plan to fix it and start giving your angry users a timescale!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:10:38.290" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="42" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="101" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:10:42.797" Score="24" ViewCount="4786" Body="&lt;p&gt;Say I've got a fresh install of Ubuntu, what steps should I take to secure it for use as a Rails application server?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="75" LastActivityDate="2010-07-29T14:21:14.887" CommunityOwnedDate="2009-05-04T17:27:25.267" Title="Securing a fresh Ubuntu server" Tags="&lt;linux&gt;&lt;ubuntu&gt;&lt;security&gt;&lt;setup&gt;&lt;application-server&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="41" />
  <row Id="43" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:12:10.720" Score="7" ViewCount="927" Body="&lt;p&gt;Users often run bandwidth intensive applications - peer-to-peer applications, video, etc. Do you monitor and/or cap per-user bandwidth?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:34:49.633" Title="How should I manage per-user bandwidth?" Tags="&lt;bandwidth&gt;" AnswerCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="44" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="84" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:12:37.643" Score="175" ViewCount="15339" Body="&lt;p&gt;As the question states, what are the most commonly used tools used for this task and what are their strengths and weaknesses?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="212" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-12-10T22:00:06.003" LastActivityDate="2011-08-03T19:55:52.547" CommunityOwnedDate="2009-05-05T00:16:49.273" Title="What tool do you use to monitor your servers?" Tags="&lt;monitoring&gt;&lt;tools&gt;&lt;server-management&gt;" AnswerCount="73" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="207" />
  <row Id="45" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="132" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:12:46.613" Score="5" ViewCount="1416" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been using VMWare to simulate a simple LAN (a DC and several workstations hosted on a single machine).  The LAN will be used as a test environment for software that is currently in development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the current requirement is simply to provide a virtual LAN, it would be ideal if we could also simulate various problems that might be encountered in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've used VMWare simply because I don't know of any alternatives.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can you recommend alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="56" LastActivityDate="2009-12-02T19:57:16.120" Title="What software is available to simulate a LAN?" Tags="&lt;networking&gt;&lt;vmware-workstation&gt;&lt;virtualization&gt;" AnswerCount="9" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="46" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="33" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:13:32.183" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes you can, it is perfectly possible. Its not a great Idea to have Exchange and AD on the same machine, it makes your network a little less secure - if Exchange is compromised then its likely your AD infrastructure will be as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However MS do it with their SBS product and many many small business do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, if you using server 2008, you must use Exchange 2007 Sp1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:13:32.183" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="47" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="69" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:13:50.467" Score="2" ViewCount="143" Body="&lt;p&gt;When setting up php on a new Unix-based server, are there any default PHP settings that you will always change? Any that you will always consider changing based on the particular environment?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="34" LastActivityDate="2009-05-02T22:00:41.460" Title="Change Default Config Settings for PHP?" Tags="&lt;linux&gt;&lt;php&gt;&lt;unix&gt;" AnswerCount="3" />
  <row Id="48" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:14:03.397" Score="20" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I always format / install. NEVER upgrade. Keep it nice and clean. too many places crap can get lost or dup'd.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But if u mean going from older version to a new version, it's generally &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having to re-install everything again.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;edit: This is referring to Windows OS, not linux, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="58" LastEditorUserId="58" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T23:53:33.997" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T23:53:33.997" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="49" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="30" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:00.463" Score="9" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Immediately book a flight to a non-extradition country&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:15:00.463" />
  <row Id="50" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:12.163" Score="13" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Because instead of having to limit their opportunities in developing new features due to backward compatibility, they can now basically say screw it. By bundling a virtualized version of the previous OS, it won't impact things as much when they change interfaces, system APIs etcetera - basically enabling them to be more innovative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it'll also ensure 100% compatibility, which is otherwise a major reason for enterprise clients not to upgrade OSs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:15:12.163" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="51" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:49.243" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;In a lot of cases, the compatibility of important software is not known. It may be even worse if the software was not updated since some time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="84" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:15:49.243" />
  <row Id="52" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="68" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:57.060" Score="9" ViewCount="2131" Body="&lt;p&gt;What Backup solutions do people use for Exchange 2007? In particular i'm interested in those that allow a mailbox level backup, so that individual mailboxes can be restored.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-12-01T14:21:04.423" Title="Backup Solutions for Exchange 2007" Tags="&lt;backup&gt;&lt;email&gt;&lt;exchange&gt;&lt;exchange-2007&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="5" />
  <row Id="53" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:15:57.433" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I absolutely agree.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As I understand it, XPM does require some more modern processors&#xA;and the extra RAM that we all understand is required for VMs.  So there is going to be some friction for the business that really have to keep their legacy applications but also want to keep their current or older hardware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="52" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:15:57.433" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="54" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="73" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:16:23.767" Score="1" ViewCount="150" Body="&lt;p&gt;I wish to migrate all our data from an existing (working) exchange 2003 server to exchange 2008. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone have any tutorials, clues or steps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It's also on windows small business server, but i'm pretty sure that shouldn't be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="58" LastEditorUserId="7342" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-06-06T08:42:21.397" LastActivityDate="2009-06-06T08:42:21.397" Title="How can i migrate all my data from Exchange 2003 to Exchange 2007?" Tags="&lt;backup&gt;&lt;exchange&gt;&lt;exchange-2007&gt;&lt;exchange-2003&gt;&lt;migrate&gt;" AnswerCount="1" />
  <row Id="55" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:17:00.113" Score="2" ViewCount="108" Body="&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IE works if you're running a Microsoft stack and force automatic updates&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Firefox is less of an attack vector, but can be harder to support due to the proliferation of extensions users install.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anything else?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:57:21.310" Title="Which browser do you prefer from a user-support perspective?" Tags="&lt;support&gt;&lt;browsers&gt;" AnswerCount="5" />
  <row Id="56" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="66" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:17:02.877" Score="4" ViewCount="232" Body="&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to keep operating temperatures and fan noise down what is the best way to clean out a server or desktop that has accumulated dust in the case, motherboard and fans? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there 'maintenance' best practices for computers out on the shop floor?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="61" LastEditorUserId="61" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T09:05:52.353" LastActivityDate="2009-05-19T06:31:55.257" Title="Desktop/Server physical maintenance" Tags="&lt;hardware&gt;&lt;maintenance&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="57" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="80" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:17:28.787" Score="6" ViewCount="1077" Body="&lt;p&gt;For a unit test server (TeamCity Agent) - is there any reason to choose old (and reliable?) Win2003 SP2 over Server 2008, assuming both are available and the machine is decent?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="88" LastActivityDate="2009-05-31T15:14:21.270" Title="Any reason to use Windows Server 2003 over Server 2008?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;windows-server-2003&gt;&lt;windows-server-2008&gt;" AnswerCount="10" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="58" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:17:36.383" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;1) Yes, Microsoft has always provided backwards compatibility, but it comes at a &lt;strong&gt;massive&lt;/strong&gt; cost, shipping a virtualised OS significantly reduces this cost.&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;2) Yes, that's the point of having the virtual OS running alongside the main OS - the user won't be able to tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="94" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:17:36.383" />
  <row Id="59" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="70" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:18:13.137" Score="18" ViewCount="775" Body="&lt;p&gt;I need an open source disk imaging application (something like Ghost or Acronis). Which one would you suggest?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="99" LastEditorUserId="123" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-05T04:29:15.627" LastActivityDate="2009-06-01T08:21:01.837" Title="Open Source Image Software" Tags="&lt;tools&gt;&lt;opensource&gt;&lt;image&gt;" AnswerCount="9" FavoriteCount="17" />
  <row Id="60" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="107" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:18:29.127" Score="6" ViewCount="2253" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm having trouble setting up Apache with mod_rewrite on my development machine. Mod_rewrite is active, and works well for some rules. Some rules do not work as intended, like this one:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;RewriteRule ^static/([^/]+)/([^/]+)     /static.php?sISOCode=$1&amp;amp;sPage=$2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In static.php I do this (for debugging):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php&#xA;print_r($_GET); print_r($_POST); print_r($_SERVER); die();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which prints (removed some items from the $_SERVER array):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Array&#xA;(&#xA;)&#xA;Array&#xA;(&#xA;)&#xA;Array&#xA;(&#xA;    [SERVER_SIGNATURE] =&amp;gt; &amp;lt;address&amp;gt;Apache/2.2.11 (Ubuntu) PHP/5.2.6-3ubuntu4.1 with Suhosin-Patch Server at alpha.prove.no Port 80&amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;&#xA;    [SERVER_SOFTWARE] =&amp;gt; Apache/2.2.11 (Ubuntu) PHP/5.2.6-3ubuntu4.1 with Suhosin-Patch&#xA;    [SERVER_ADDR] =&amp;gt; 127.0.0.1&#xA;    [SERVER_PORT] =&amp;gt; 80&#xA;    [REMOTE_ADDR] =&amp;gt; 127.0.0.1&#xA;    [DOCUMENT_ROOT] =&amp;gt; /home/veg/workspace/project&#xA;    [SERVER_ADMIN] =&amp;gt; webmaster@localhost&#xA;    [SCRIPT_FILENAME] =&amp;gt; /home/veg/workspace/project/static.php&#xA;    [REMOTE_PORT] =&amp;gt; 38954&#xA;    [GATEWAY_INTERFACE] =&amp;gt; CGI/1.1&#xA;    [SERVER_PROTOCOL] =&amp;gt; HTTP/1.1&#xA;    [REQUEST_METHOD] =&amp;gt; GET&#xA;    [QUERY_STRING] =&amp;gt; &#xA;    [REQUEST_URI] =&amp;gt; /static/no/startCar&#xA;    [SCRIPT_NAME] =&amp;gt; /static.php&#xA;    [PATH_INFO] =&amp;gt; /no/startCar&#xA;    [PATH_TRANSLATED] =&amp;gt; redirect:/index.php/startCar&#xA;    [PHP_SELF] =&amp;gt; /static.php/no/startCar&#xA;    [argv] =&amp;gt; Array&#xA;        (&#xA;        )&#xA;    [argc] =&amp;gt; 0&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Somehow the GET parameters set according to the rule is not getting through. The same .htaccess file is in use on other setups, and works well. The Apache configuration for this virtual domain:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;VirtualHost *:80&amp;gt;&#xA;        ServerAdmin webmaster@localhost&#xA;        ServerName project.example.com&#xA;&#xA;        DocumentRoot /home/veg/workspace/project&#xA;        &amp;lt;Directory /home/veg/workspace/project&amp;gt;&#xA;                Options Indexes FollowSymLinks MultiViews&#xA;                AllowOverride All&#xA;                Order allow,deny&#xA;                allow from all&#xA;        &amp;lt;/Directory&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;        ErrorLog /var/log/apache2/error.log&#xA;&#xA;        # Possible values include: debug, info, notice, warn, error, crit,&#xA;        # alert, emerg.&#xA;        LogLevel warn&#xA;&#xA;        CustomLog /var/log/apache2/access.log combined&#xA;&amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The access log and error log outputs nothing when this happens. Any ideas appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An example of a rule that works, for the same file:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;RewriteRule ^faq/?$                   /static.php?sISOCode=no&amp;amp;sPage=faq&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="41" LastEditorUserId="41" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:25:30.517" LastActivityDate="2010-09-10T05:45:09.163" Title="mod_rewrite does not forward GET parameters" Tags="&lt;apache&gt;&lt;php&gt;&lt;mod-rewrite&gt;&lt;rewrite&gt;" AnswerCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="61" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="35" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:18:34.137" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;For monitoring, I would say something like Cacti, Ganglia or Munin. And for alerts, I would use Nagios.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For spot monitoring, ntop is useful for a quick graphical overview. One could always use netstat or tcpdump if you are into the command line stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="97" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:18:34.137" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="62" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="4300" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:18:58.050" Score="3" ViewCount="492" Body="&lt;p&gt;On the limited (Cisco) VPN systems that I've used, the VPN connectivity is broken when my computer is put to sleep and must be re-established on wakeup. Is this a necessary property of VPN?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="100" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T20:17:00.910" Title="Why do VPN connections break when I sleep my computer?" Tags="&lt;vpn&gt;&lt;connectivity&gt;" AnswerCount="4" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="63" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:19:06.240" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Virtual PC bundling is a big deal, but I think XP Mode will be bigger. Most people don't care about the fact that they're running in a VM, they just want their old programs to work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:19:06.240" />
  <row Id="64" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="5921" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:19:23.463" Score="0" ViewCount="69" Body="&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Search Server 2008 and other MS serach products are tuned by editing the HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Office Server\12.0\Search\Setup\ContentIndexCommon registry key. Is there an utility for doing the same?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastActivityDate="2009-05-07T18:01:55.547" Title="Is there an utility for editing the MS Search Server 2008 registry settings?" Tags="&lt;sharepoint&gt;&lt;search&gt;&lt;search-server&gt;" AnswerCount="1" />
  <row Id="65" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:02.713" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;For me, it has to be downtime &amp;amp; loss of productivity.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the desktop front, even though I try and keep my system relatively &quot;clean&quot; in terms of what is installed, it is still set up exactly how I need it.  In the past, I've found it takes 2 or 3 days per year's worth of data / applications / settings to migrate to a clean OS install: with data being the most time consuming - checking out scores of projects from a half dozen different SVN repositories just isn't a quick process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the server front, &quot;upgrade&quot; is a bit of a misnomer: I would never ever upgrade the entire OS of a server whilst it was &quot;live&quot;: critical patches would be as far as I went (if it ain't broke, don't fix it).  When choosing a new server, it really depends on the requirements, but others have said, it's not really worth the hassle of being on the crest of the wave with a new OS - let others who can afford to throw money at problems trial and error it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="40" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:02.713" />
  <row Id="66" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="56" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:07.860" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;This really depends on the specific casings involved in each, er, case.  Generally I find that a vacuum cleaner is my best friend when cleaning out equipment.  If there are speed settings then set them down relatively low.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also buy special computer attachments for some vacuum cleaners, for getting into smaller spaces etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For tougher things it is sometimes handy to have access to an air compressor - we used to have one of these floating around at work for cleaning purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="86" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:07.860" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="67" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="59" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:09.263" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've heard good things about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fogproject.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FOG&lt;/a&gt; as a Ghost alternative. No personal experience to back that up, however, as I used a custom PXE solution before FOG was available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="100" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:09.263" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="68" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="52" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:23.943" Score="8" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/systemcenter/dataprotectionmanager/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DPM&lt;/a&gt; is an amazingly good backup tool. It does mail box level backups for Exchange. In addition to being able to backup files, SQL Server, and SharePoint. The SharePoint backup is better than EVERY other tool out there (right down to file level).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="103" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:23.943" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="69" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="47" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:24.957" Score="7" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;A default installation of PHP on a UNIX server pretty much works out of the box. Much of the configuration depends on your desired usage of the server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here's what I do:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change &lt;code&gt;upload_max_filesize&lt;/code&gt; from the default value (2M) to something higher.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install and enable the modules that I use most often:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;php5-gd&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;php5-cli&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;php5-suhosin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;php5-curl&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But again: most of the configuration is dependent on what you use the server for, which makes it hard to provide a simple answer to this question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:24.957" />
  <row Id="70" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="59" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:20:35.240" Score="15" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I like GParted and CloneZilla. GParted is my favorite for single-use, CloneZilla's best when you need to blast images out across the network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:20:35.240" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="71" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="62" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:21:20.510" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm not exactly sure but my guess is because the network card (NIC) has been disconnected from the operating system stack. The fact that a VPN connection remains open is not so much hardware related but more by the software layers (think back to your 7 layer architecture).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="58" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:21:20.510" />
  <row Id="72" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="10" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:21:55.360" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The only multi-machine mixed Mac OS X and Windows backup system I've used is Dantz Retrospect; Dantz was bought by EMC several years back, and Retrospect is still a living product.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My experience back in the late 1990s through early 2000s was that they provided a great incremental backup tool for multiple systems on a LAN.  It did take them a release to shake out their Windows and Mac OS X support but once they did, I started hearing good things about their Windows backup solutions too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in the early 2000s their Windows and Windows Server (including Exchange) backup support was good enough that it resulted in a department of a Very Large Company that I was doing some consulting for to switch to Retrospect.  I was doing software development for them, not systems/network administration; it was the Windows people at their site who discovered and dove into Retrospect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:21:55.360" />
  <row Id="73" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="54" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:22:01.053" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's very straightforward. Here is a good tutorial for migrating from older versions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msexchange.org/tutorials/Transitioning-Exchange-2000-2003-Exchange-Server-2007-Part1.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Transitioning from Exchange 2000/2003 to Exchange Server 2007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some things you'll have to do in order to prepare your domain for Exchange Server 2007, though:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preparing Active Directory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare Legacy Exchange Permissions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare Schema&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PrepareDomain and PrepareAllDomains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version of Exchange Best Practices Analyzer Tool, which you can download at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.exbpa.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.exbpa.com&lt;/a&gt;, includes an Exchange 2007 Readiness Check option.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="45" LastEditorUserId="45" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:29:20.333" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:29:20.333" />
  <row Id="74" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:22:10.837" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;The answer as always is &quot;it depends&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For certain enterprise storage (say EMC), the vendor will specifically qualify drives and even go to the extent of loading custom firmware. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Mark says, I find it to be the best when you follow a vendor's approved list if there is one. The initial cost savings is outweighed by the time spent trying to hunt down gremlins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="97" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:22:10.837" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="75" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="62" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:22:39.897" Score="10" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Because VPN is a not a stateless communication system like HTTP, it needs to have continuous connection. And since the OS is sleeping, it'll no longer maintain the connection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:22:39.897" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="76" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="40" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:22:44.873" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xs4all.nl/~edienske/abaktu/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.xs4all.nl/~edienske/abaktu/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It does excellent backups and is configured in 5 minutes in a small xml file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We nightly dump the IIS XML config into a directory  using Iisback.vbs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check it out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/prodtechnol/WindowsServer2003/Library/IIS/5e7e923c-b374-4872-a8f5-da85ec1315fd.mspx?mfr=true&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/prodtechnol/WindowsServer2003/Library/IIS/5e7e923c-b374-4872-a8f5-da85ec1315fd.mspx?mfr=true&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="77" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:22:44.873" />
  <row Id="77" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="55" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:23:06.090" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of supporting web applications: literally anything other than IE6 would be just fine!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="40" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:23:06.090" />
  <row Id="78" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="30" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:23:17.650" Score="21" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Don't Panic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="97" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:23:17.650" CommentCount="5" />
  <row Id="79" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="151" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:23:18.507" Score="21" ViewCount="1206" Body="&lt;p&gt;What's your system recovery CD? I've used Ultimate Boot CD and GParted. What works for you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastEditorUserId="1349" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-27T21:39:05.460" LastActivityDate="2010-11-06T09:37:51.080" Title="Favorite system recovery Live CD?" Tags="&lt;live-cd&gt;&lt;system-restore&gt;" AnswerCount="9" FavoriteCount="20" />
  <row Id="80" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="57" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:23:49.927" Score="18" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I can't think of any reason at all to choose Server 2003 over Server 2008 other than licensing costs. (as in, 2003 would be cheaper.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Server 2008 has already had one service pack and is plenty mature. It also has a lot of fundamental improvements in IIS, the networking stack, etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:23:49.927" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="81" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="30" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:23:59.847" Score="7" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Check the basics first, it seems silly, but things like &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is the power on at the server facility? (if you host off-site)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is your hosting provider down?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know that a lot of time can be wasted looking for a solution when the problem is upstream&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:23:59.847" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="82" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="7" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:24:39.613" Score="1" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;avast! Professional Edition has some nice features like creating a preconfigured installation, background scanning (doesn't hog the hard drive while the computer is under load) and can be configured to be user-friendly in not dropping millions of notifications on him. There are some server products avast! authors offer, like avast! Distributed Network Manager.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At my side IT job I only used the client Professional Edition, without the management server or DNM and it worked very well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="36" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:24:39.613" />
  <row Id="83" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="40" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:24:52.327" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;We've been using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iis.net/extensions/webdeploymenttool&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;web deployment tool&lt;/a&gt; (aka msdeploy) to sync our main web server with our failover servers. It's great - it'll migrate permissions, IIS configuration, virtual directories, files, folders; in fact, we used it to mirror our main web server onto a fresh Windows 2008 box in about ten minutes, and it just worked - really impressive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It's the best way we've found of capturing IIS files and configuration state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="79" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:24:52.327" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="84" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="44" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:25:04.090" Score="123" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nagios.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; title=&quot;Nagios&quot;&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; in the past with success. It's very extensible (over 200 add-ons), relatively easy to use and lots of reports. A negative would be the initial setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="61" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:25:04.090" CommunityOwnedDate="2009-05-05T00:16:49.273" CommentCount="13" />
  <row Id="85" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="47" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:25:15.633" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;There isn't something that I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; change. Actually, there's rarely anything I change, for &lt;em&gt;any given installation&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it's my own for-development-and-play-server, I probably max out the permissions to do anything, but when deploying a server for something specific, I want to have the PHP as strict as possible, without affecting the functionality of the scripts too much.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="102" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:25:15.633" />
  <row Id="86" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="102" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:25:30.047" Score="7" ViewCount="1007" Body="&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a lot of confusion around having multiple partitions for Windows. Some of the theories I have heard are&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It's faster to move to a new partition start than searching for a file start&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you need to format it's easier since the data is on the other partition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Putting swap file on a separate partition increases performance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;File/Folder level security&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally I found the data one to be true, but in that scenario I would rather have separate disks since those will be faster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short my question is, is there any truth to the above theories and are there any other reasons to partition a disk?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="103" LastEditorUserId="4" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-06T04:22:28.507" LastActivityDate="2009-08-04T16:35:25.197" Title="Are there good reasons to partition disks on Windows?" Tags="&lt;windows&gt;&lt;partition&gt;" AnswerCount="6" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="87" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="30" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:25:54.507" Score="5" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I ping stuff. What happens after that varies greatly depending on the results of the ping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="79" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:25:54.507" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="88" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="176" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:26:04.820" Score="6" ViewCount="1281" Body="&lt;p&gt;Users are reporting that it's taking a long time to access files on the network, browse intranet sites, etc. What should I check?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:32:08.687" Title="Slow network speeds - what should I check?" Tags="&lt;bandwidth&gt;&lt;troubleshooting&gt;" AnswerCount="4" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="89" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="211" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:26:22.167" Score="6" ViewCount="676" Body="&lt;p&gt;What kind of optimization (performance or whatever) do you use when going live with IIS (on windows 2003) ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, I use 1 application pool per web site, but I think I can do more :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="110" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:34:22.833" LastActivityDate="2009-07-11T21:53:44.393" Title="IIS Optimization" Tags="&lt;iis&gt;&lt;performance&gt;&lt;optimization&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="90" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="44" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:26:28.720" Score="51" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Personally, I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://munin.projects.linpro.no/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; title=&quot;Munin&quot;&gt;Munin&lt;/a&gt; which is very easy to install and to write plugins for as it has a very straightforward architecture. There are quite many plugins already around for all the purposes you could imagine, so you probably won't even have to write plugins in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also provides beautiful graphs and the option to configure (very basic) alerts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="98" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:26:28.720" CommunityOwnedDate="2009-05-05T00:16:49.273" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="91" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="59" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:26:29.297" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I use dd. =D&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="97" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:26:29.297" />
  <row Id="92" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="62" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:26:53.070" Score="0" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Bingo. Most VPN software is implemented using the TCP/IP stack, which is not stateless. They have timeouts associated with the connections and when you put your computer to sleep there's no way to keep that connection alive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="112" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:26:53.070" />
  <row Id="93" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="86" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:28:21.180" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Putting swap on a different disk will not be faster since it's still the same physical disk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, by partitioning you can actually determine whether the partitions should be on the inner or outer part of the physical disk (depending on partition order). Thus you can make one partition on the outer edge of the disk that's way faster than the one on the inner part of the disk. Putting swap there might theoretically increase performance. It might also increase disk thrashing since the disk head will have to move from the innermost part to the outermost more often.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:28:21.180" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="94" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="55" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:28:58.027" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Firefox MSI with lockdown features through Group Policies like FrontMotion's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frontmotion.com/FMFirefoxCE/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Firefox Community Edition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="36" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:28:58.027" />
  <row Id="95" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="117" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:29:13.080" Score="4" ViewCount="237" Body="&lt;p&gt;What's your top trick for getting a new employee set up quickly? Do you use images, scripts, something else?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastEditorUserId="32" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-20T07:11:11.473" LastActivityDate="2009-05-20T07:11:11.473" CommunityOwnedDate="2009-05-20T07:11:11.473" Title="How do you optimize new user setup?" Tags="&lt;user-management&gt;&lt;automation&gt;&lt;tips&gt;&lt;recruitment&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="5" />
  <row Id="96" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="110" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:29:13.300" Score="1" ViewCount="262" Body="&lt;p&gt;Very simply what software KVM's would you recommend for using on Windows?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="103" LastEditorUserId="103" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T13:06:31.917" LastActivityDate="2009-05-13T01:30:35.180" Title="Software KVM" Tags="&lt;software&gt;&lt;kvm&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="97" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="55" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:01.970" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'd go with Firefox, but I know what you mean about the plugins.  Is there a way to restrict plugin installation with policy settings (or even better restrict to a certain subset of plugins)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:30:01.970" />
  <row Id="98" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="21" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:03.470" Score="1" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I subscribe to the &quot;If it ain't broke&quot; policy, especially on server versions.  Having to go through the pain of working out how to get everything up and working in the new version tends to keep me with the version I currently have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only when the new features become essential and required do I feel the need to go through the process again.  And then only when the new essential features outweigh the process of working out how to get everything working again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="115" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:30:03.470" />
  <row Id="99" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="134" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:04.577" Score="0" ViewCount="106" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm more specifically looking to set the Expires and the Last-Modified headers on static content (images, css, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T08:46:10.467" LastActivityDate="2009-07-14T13:47:34.983" Title="How do you send the response headers in IIS?" Tags="&lt;iis&gt;&lt;response&gt;&lt;webadmin&gt;" AnswerCount="2" />
  <row Id="100" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="108" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:15.027" Score="3" ViewCount="261" Body="&lt;p&gt;I want to use my external USB hdd formatted as NTFS on my Mac and want full read/write previledge there. I know there are third party drivers to accomplish this (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/macfuse/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MacFUSE&lt;/a&gt;) but I want to know how stable do you think to use such tools?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="107" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:33:02.183" Title="Is writing on NTFS partition from mac os considered safe now?" Tags="&lt;mac&gt;&lt;macosx&gt;" AnswerCount="1" />
  <row Id="101" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="42" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:30:43.467" Score="18" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I can't think of any Ubuntu-specific tweaks, but here's a few that apply to all distributions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Uninstall all unnecessary packages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use public-key only authentication in SSH&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Disable root logins via SSH (doesn't apply to Ubuntu)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the production settings for PHP (php.ini-recommended)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure MySQL to use sockets only&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course this list isn't complete, and you'll never be completely safe, but it covers all the exploits &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; have seen in real life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, the exploits I have seen were almost always related to unsecure user code, not unsecure configuration. The default configurations in minimal, server distributions tend to be pretty secure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="89" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:30:43.467" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="102" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="86" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:31:08.270" Score="26" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;One of the primary reasons I use different partitions is that of separating the data from the OS. Should you need to re-install windows (which we all know is quite likely) at any point you can do so without needing to move your data off to somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As partitions on the same disk will be using the same spindle theres very little to be gained in terms of speed with partitioning a single disk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:31:08.270" CommentCount="1" />
</posts>
  <row Id="104" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:31:33.760" Score="18" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;On Linux/Debian based systems, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/search?keywords=cron-apt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;cron-apt&lt;/a&gt; is a very handy tool that can manage automating apt via cron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'm using it to &lt;code&gt;apt-get update&lt;/code&gt; every day and send me an email if new updates has to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian-administration.org/articles/162&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;short and well-done introduction on that tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="117" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:31:33.760" />
  <row Id="107" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="60" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:32:43.320" Score="12" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Have you tried using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.2/mod/mod%5Frewrite.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;QSA (Query String Append)&lt;/a&gt; flag?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;RewriteRule ^static/([^/]+)/([^/]+) /static.php?sISOCode=$1&amp;amp;sPage=$2 [QSA]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT, AND ACTUAL ANSWER BELOW:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This problem is caused by Apache's &lt;a href=&quot;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.2/content-negotiation.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;mod_negotiation&lt;/a&gt;, in particular the MultiViews option you are using:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The effect of MultiViews is as&#xA;  follows: if the server receives a&#xA;  request for /some/dir/foo, if&#xA;  /some/dir has MultiViews enabled, and&#xA;  /some/dir/foo does not exist, then the&#xA;  server reads the directory looking for&#xA;  files named foo.*, and effectively&#xA;  fakes up a type map which names all&#xA;  those files, assigning them the same&#xA;  media types and content-encodings it&#xA;  would have if the client had asked for&#xA;  one of them by name. It then chooses&#xA;  the best match to the client's&#xA;  requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enabling Multiviews tells Apache to guess which file to use when the URI does not actually point to an existing location.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disable multiviews by either using &lt;code&gt;-MultiViews&lt;/code&gt; in your .htaccess or leaving it out all together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="22" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T09:16:45.650" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:16:45.650" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="108" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="100" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:33:02.183" Score="11" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;MacFuse runs very well here and I never had any problems leading to data loss - in fact I never had any problems to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is one issue though: When a NTFS volume is not cleanly unmounted, NTFS-3g refuses to mount the disk in RW mode (it can be forced to do so though) and there are no tools available to clear that not-cleanly-unmounted flag from MacOS, which means that basically, you still need a Windows installation around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="98" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:33:02.183" />
  <row Id="110" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="96" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:33:25.957" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://synergy2.sourceforge.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://synergy2.sourceforge.net&lt;/a&gt; with some success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is cross platform, lets you move your mouse off the edge of one screen and onto the next screen even across systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="133" LastEditorUserId="133" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-12T22:06:08.150" LastActivityDate="2009-05-12T22:06:08.150" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="117" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="95" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:34:12.430" Score="6" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Ghosted images that then run a user customisation script work well.  Give the user all the basic stuff (OS, Office, Firefox, misc corporate software) and then get the server to allocate shared drives and exchange on first login.  This is of course a windows-centric answer :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should also mention, for developer machines, I would then back off and let a higher level of customisation. But then I'm biased.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastEditorUserId="38" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-05-04T00:27:57.523" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T00:27:57.523" />
  <row Id="132" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="45" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:38:57.300" Score="7" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;VMWare is a very strong solution. You should look at creating a team in VMWare Workstation to bring up your mini LAN. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tends to mimic reality very well and can be reconfigured on the fly. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unless you have something very strange in mind, VMWare workstation can help you simulate just about anything a real LAN could encounter. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="63" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:38:57.300" />
  <row Id="134" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="99" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:40:34.147" Score="3" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;IIS Admin, go to the properties of the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click on HTTP Headers then set the content expiration values.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best way to set it on static content is to just keep all the static content in a 'Content' folder away from dynamic files&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:40:34.147" />
  <row Id="151" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="79" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:44:53.557" Score="12" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trinityhome.org/Home/index.php?content=TRINITY_RESCUE_KIT_DOWNLOAD&amp;amp;front_id=12&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;locale=en&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Trinity Rescue Kit&lt;/a&gt; (version 3.4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;It is possible to boot TRK in three different ways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;as a bootable CD which you can burn yourself from a downloadable isofile or a self burning Windows executable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;from a USB stick/disk (optionally also a fixed disk), installable from Windows or from the bootable TRK cd (which is easier and safer)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;from network over PXE: you start 1 TRK from CD or USB and you run all other computers from that one over the network without modifying anything to you local network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Here 's a sumup of some of the most important features, new and old:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;easily reset windows passwords with the improved winpass tool&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;simple and easy menu interface&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;5 different virusscan products integrated in a single uniform commandline with online update capability&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;full ntfs write support thanks to ntfs-3g&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;winclean, a utility that cleans up all sorts of unnecessary temporary files on your computer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;clone computers over the network via multicast&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;wide range of hardware support (kernel 2.6.35)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;contributed backup utility called &quot;pi&quot;, to automate local machine backups&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;easy script to find and mount all local filesystems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;self update capability to include and update all virusscanners + local changes you made to TRK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;full proxyserver support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;run a samba fileserver (windows like filesharing)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;run a ssh server&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;recovery and undeletion of files with utilities and procedures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;recovery of lost partitions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;evacuation of dying disks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;full read/write and rpm support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;UTF-8 international character support (select keyboard language from the scrollable textmenu at startup)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;2 rootkit detection uitilities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;most software updated to recent versions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;literally thousands of changes and bugfixes since version 3.3&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;li&gt;elaborated documentation, including manpages for all commands (also TRK 's own)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="160" LastEditorUserId="160" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2010-11-06T09:37:51.080" LastActivityDate="2010-11-06T09:37:51.080" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="152" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="15" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:44:55.477" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been running soft raid5 on Ubuntu since 6.10, and always upgraded without problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that in Jaunty (9.04), which is not LTS, there's a bug where degraded arrays don't start automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="28" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T08:44:55.477" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="176" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="88" CreationDate="2009-04-30T08:56:05.747" Score="6" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To check the latency on a network:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run a continuous ping from the command line:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ping -t [destination IP DNS or hostname]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From your PC to the users PC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your PC to the file server&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your PC to Internet sites&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If any of these are slow, then run:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tracert [destination IP DNS or hostname]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to see where the issue is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To check the bandwidth of a network:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need to install bandwidth monitoring software, look at your network switches (if they support monitoring), look at router logs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://performit.co.uk/network/troubleshooting.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://performit.co.uk/network/troubleshooting.php&lt;/a&gt; has some good tips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="137" LastEditorUserId="137" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2009-04-30T09:32:08.687" LastActivityDate="2009-05-05T14:16:43.390" />
  <row Id="211" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="89" CreationDate="2009-04-30T09:14:38.667" Score="4" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Even on large banks, I've rarely (can't remember when) done any optimizations on IIS that weren't just the addition of modules. I keep all the defaults.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dynamic and Static Compression&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set Expires dates on Static content, images, JS, etc&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="209" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T09:14:38.667" />
  <row Id="394" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="12" CreationDate="2009-04-30T11:16:26.097" Score="1" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;Have just found out what the problem was (well, my hosting provider did). Changed code by adding '%COMSPEC% /C' (where %COMSPEC% holds the path to cmd.exe) to the front of the command.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dim cmd : cmd = &quot;%COMSPEC% /C sqlcmd -S &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_SERVER &amp;amp; &quot; -U &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_UID &amp;amp; &quot; -P &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_PWD &amp;amp; &quot; -d &quot; &amp;amp; DATABASE_NAME &amp;amp; &quot; -i &quot;&quot;&quot; &amp;amp; scriptPath &amp;amp; &quot;&quot;&quot; -b&quot;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It now works just dandy. I'm not sure about the whys/hows so I'll leave the question unanswered for now for someone to answer more comprehensively if they can.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T11:16:26.097" />
  <row Id="493" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="26" CreationDate="2009-04-30T11:59:51.653" Score="6" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, you need to zoom out to the bigger picture and ask what it means to administer Windows and SQL Servers.  For example, how many of these other things do you have in your environment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third party backup products like NetBackup or BackupExec&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Antivirus products&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Storage tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Firewalls or web filtering software&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hardware alerting (like IBM Director or HP SIM)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of these things have their own mechanisms for management, and since PowerShell is still relatively new, not all services will be PowerShell-enabled.  For now, you may need to jump out of PowerShell in order to manage things like those.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, there's no other language that works better across all of those Windows tools either.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you say &quot;functionality to administer servers&quot;, that doesn't come from a Windows language yet.  In the *nix world, you can stay inside a scripting environment, but the Windows world isn't quite there yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="431" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T11:59:51.653" CommentCount="6" />
  <row Id="509" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2009-04-30T12:06:00.580" Score="11" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;If you switch over to full recovery mode, you can do this with filegroups, but it's really, really clumsy.  You leave the data in the primary filegroup, and put the indexes in a separate (non-default, that's the key) filegroup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then you stagger your backups so that you're doing filegroup backups of the primary every night, and transaction log backups every X minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When disaster strikes, you restore the primary filegroup by itself.  The data is suddenly online, but the indexes are not.  However, to get back to normalcy, you'll need to export that data into a new clean database and add indexes from there.  You can't bring the database completely online without restoring all of the filegroups, and you can't say &quot;I don't need that other filegroup anymore anyway.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more about how this works, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://sqlserverpedia.com/wiki/Filegroup%5FRestore%5FScript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;video tutorial on filegroup restores.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="431" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T12:06:00.580" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="537" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2009-04-30T12:16:18.353" Score="15" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;There's two parts to this question: when to add a new FILEGROUP, and when to add a new FILE in a filegroup.  First let's talk theory:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark's right about the primary reason being performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The secondary reason is disaster recovery.  With SQL Server 2005 and newer, you can do filegroup restores.  When disaster strikes, you can restore just your primary filegroup first and bring the database partially online for queries.  Users can run queries while you're restoring other filegroups.  This is useful for databases with a large amount of historical data that may not be required right away, or data warehouses that need to load data into current tables without needing historical data for access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another reason is the read/write profile of groups of data.  If you have some data that is constantly written to, and other data that gets heavy read activity, you can build different types of storage to accommodate those needs.  You could put the heavy-write stuff on raid 10, and leave the read-biased stuff on cheaper raid 5.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, let's talk files versus filegroups.  When you place objects in SQL Server, you have to place them at the filegroup level.  You can land a table or an index in a filegroup, but you can't pick a specific file.  So everything we've discussed so far has been about when to add a filegroup - but when do you add a file?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you're designing storage, and you have 80 hard drives, there's a few ways you can break it up:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One pool of 80 drives&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Two pools of 40 drives&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Four pools of 20 drives, etc...&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Different storage subsystems have different performance profiles.  I've worked with some SANs that performed best with 12-16 drive arrays, and anything larger than that didn't have a performance improvement.  Another example is SANs with multipathing: if you have several HBAs connecting your server to your storage, and if your multipathing software isn't real active/active, then you may need one array per path in order to distribute load.  Four paths, four pools of drives will get better performance on those types of drives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In those cases, you end up with four different arrays, four different drives under Windows (unless you use mount points, and even then it's different folders) and you'll need four separate files in SQL Server.  Those separate files can be in the same filegroup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="431" LastActivityDate="2009-04-30T12:16:18.353" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="1238" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2009-04-30T16:42:53.610" Score="6" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, I have encountered this with low-end cards and buggy drivers. However, &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;, not on an up-to-date Adaptec rebranded card. Wow is all I can say. One thing to consider, maybe it is more a bug with the drive than the RAID controller.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don't have a good answer, but since you seem to have exhausted most of your options other than replacing the card, (and replacing the drives did the trick) here's a few ideas you can consider for your troubleshooting:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The WD drives were RE (RAID Edition) drives, right?&lt;/strong&gt; The time limited error recovery is important, so if you don't have that and the drive is attempting to recover the sector, you are going to get a looooong pause from that drive. If the RAID controller is being patient and not dropping the drive you'll have a big problem on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the SMART data on the drives&lt;/strong&gt; you removed and see if there is anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another comment about the importance of time limited error recovery (TLER) feature, from NAS / RAID vendor support:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;As I mention before, we always suggest customers to use enterprise level drives if they use the drives in RAID settings. &lt;strong&gt;Enterprise level drives have more consistent responding time so that the RAID will be safer.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="762" LastEditorUserId="1" LastEditorDisplayName="" LastEditDate="2010-08-24T09:41:35.597" LastActivityDate="2010-08-24T09:41:35.597" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="4300" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="62" CreationDate="2009-05-04T20:17:00.910" Score="2" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think Bob Somers hit the answer, but there's another possibility. You could be sleeping your computer through the rekey interval, which breaks the connection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VPNs negotiate a session key for every connection. This key gets &quot;stale&quot; after a while, and may be vulnerable to attack if enough data has been passed with it. To maintain the security of the VPN channel, there is a rekey interval where both ends automatically renegotiate a fresh session key. This is usually transparent to both sides of the tunnel, assuming both sides are connected. When you put your computer to sleep, it's possible the rekey interval is up during that time, and the VPN host closes the connection because it can't renegotiate the session key.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1129" LastActivityDate="2009-05-04T20:17:00.910" />
  <row Id="5921" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="64" CreationDate="2009-05-07T18:01:55.547" Score="1" ViewCount="" Body="&lt;p&gt;None that I know off. I search the last couple of days, trying to find a decent answer for you here. Found none.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="1797" LastActivityDate="2009-05-07T18:01:55.547" />
